# Zein Al-abbedine Youssef

# **Software Engineer**

#### **Profile**

An experienced Software Engineer that is proficient in a wide range of technologies including Angular 12, NodeJS, Salesforce, React and AWS. Has experience with building APIs, Agile development (Scrum) and system design. Has a deep understanding of the entire software development lifecycle including researching, designing and implementing changes to existing code bases.

#### Brands included: Amazon, Rocket Mortgage (Rock FOC)

### **Highlight Of Accomplishments**

- Built a microsite with thousands of daily users that was integrated with a WordPress CMS
- Worked on the back-end of an automated accounting system for a large corporation
- Thrived in a continuous improvement/continuous development (CI/CD) and Agile environment where I pushed code to production environments on a regular basis

### **Professional Experience**

#### **Full Stack Software Developer,** *Rocket Mortgage*

06/2021 - 08/2023

 Developed web applications using popular web technologies including Angular 12, NodeJS and .Net

Detroit, MI

- Worked with IAC (Terraform, CircleCI) to facilitate the automated deployment of code to production environments
- Maintained the quality and health of production applications through Dynatrace dashboards
- Worked on existing .Net APIs to update a Salesforce database

#### **Software Development Engineer,** *Amazon.com*

03/2020 - 01/2021

• Researched, designed and implemented code in Java for the back-end of an automated accounting system

Vancouver, BC

- Wrote extensive and detailed design documents and presented findings to larger engineering teams
- · Worked in an Agile environment where code was deployed frequently to production environments

## **Education**

#### **Bachelor's of Science in Computer Science,** Wayne State University

08/2015 - 05/2019

• GPA: 3.7

**Detroit, United States** 

Technical Skills: NodeJS (Express, Axios), React (Hooks), Angular (RXJS), Agile Method (Scrum), Salesforce, .Net, Python, Java, Typescript, AWS (S3, Lambda, RDS, ECS), Docker, Terraform, Dynatrace